Finding aid to Mountain Day and Picnics Files CA.MS.00021
Smith College Archives
Mountain Day and Picnics Files
1882-2008
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.00021
0.625 linear feet (2 containers)
Smith College tradition. Contains photographs, clippings, and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Arrangement
All of the materials are arranged chronologically, while undated and miscellaneous materials are located at the back of each document box.
Biographical / Historical
Mountain Day has remained a unique and much-anticipated holiday at Smith College since it was first celebrated in October 1877. According to an article written in The Sophian in 1970, "On this occasion, the date of which is unknown to all except [the college president], bells ring to announce a surprise holiday on which all academic appointments are cancelled." Students are encouraged to use this day to take long walks or bike rides and to enjoy a beautiful fall day free from the stress of everyday life.
Scope and Contents
The majority of the material is composed of photographs and newspaper clippings documenting Smith's celebration of Mountain Day from 1882 to the present.
Smith College--Mountain Day.; Smith College.
- Photos, Programs, 1882 (Box 3083)
- Program, 1883 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1884 (Box 3083)
- Programs, 1886 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1887 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1891 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1892 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1893 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1894 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1895 (Box 3083)
- Photos, Clippings, 1896 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1897 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1898 (Box 3083)
- Photos, Memorabilia, 1899 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1900 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1901 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1902 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1903 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1904 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1905 (Box 3083)
- Photos, Clippings, 1905 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1906 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1907 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1908 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1909 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1910 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1911 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1912 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1913 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1914 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1915 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1916 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, Photos, 1917 (Box 3083)
- Notes, Photos, 1918 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1923 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1925 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1927 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1928 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1930 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, Photos, 1931 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1932 (Box 3083)
- Notes, Photos, 1933 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1934 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, Photos, 1936 (Box 3083)
- Clipping, Photos, 1937 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1938 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, Photos, 1940 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, Photos, 1941 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1942 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1943 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1944 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1945 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1946 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1947 (Box 3083)
- Clippings, 1948 (Box 3083)
- Misc. Clippings, 1882-1949 (Box 3083)
- Photos, 1950 (Box 3083.1)
- Photos, 1951 (Box 3083.1)
- Photos, 1952-1953 (Box 3083.1)
- Photos, 1954 (Box 3083.1)
- Clippings, Photos, 1955-1960 (Box 3083.1)
- Clippings, Photos, 1960-1979 (Box 3083.1)
- Clippings, Photos, 1980 - (Box 3083.1)
- Clippings, Photos, undated (Box 3083.1)
- Misc. Clippings, 1950 - (Box 3083.1)
- Announcements, 2008 (Box 3083.1)